So the title, of course, is going to be the Funmi app,
标题当然就是 "Fund Me App"
which we see up here in the title section.
我们可以在这里的标题部分看到它
So let's update this HTML, so that it has those buttons,
让我们来更新一下这个 HTML，让它拥有那些按钮
and it can actually connect and work with our blockchain and work with any blockchain.
这样它才能连接和使用我们的区块链以及任何区块链
Something else that you can do in HTML is you can actually write JavaScript inside your HTML.
其实你可以直接在 HTML 里面写 JavaScript
And the way we can do that is by doing this script tag,
要想做到这一点，需要执行 ``
and then we'll do a closing script tag.
接着要闭合它 ``
And anything inside here inside of our script tags is going to be JavaScript.
在 "" 标签内部的所有内容都是 JavaScript
So I could do something like
所以我们可以这样做
console dot log, hi, with a bunch of exclamation marks, I'm going to save it.
`console.log("Hi!!")，写一些感叹号，接着保存它
We'll go back to our front end, we're going to right click, we'll hit Inspect,
我们回到前端，点击右键，选择“检查”("Inspect")
we'll go to the console. And we can see that Hi prints it out,
前往“控制台”("Console")，接着我们可以看到 "Hi" 被打印了出来
we refresh, we can see the hi consistently printed out
当我们刷新页面时，就可以看到 "Hi" 被持续打印出来
hi from script tag, we'll save it,
"Hi from script tag!"，保存一下
we'll move back, we see hi from script tag printed out.
回到前端，我们看到 "Hi from script tag!" 被打印了出来
I know it's a little bit small. So let me zoom in. Alright, great.
这里有点小，我来放大一下，很好
So we can type our JavaScript in here,
所以，我们可以在这里输入 JavaScript 代码
it's inside the script tag is where we're going to write our JavaScript to write the functions that
在 "" 标签内部编写 JavaScript 函数
our front end is going to interact with.
用它们来与前端进行交互
Now, as we saw before, in this little console, we can check for window dot Etherium,
就像我们之前见到过的，在这个小控制台("Console")中，我们可以使用 "window.ethereum" 进行检查
to see if Metamask or is installed.
来查看是否安装了 MetaMask
And again, a lot of what we're working with is actually right in the Metamask documentation.
再次重申，我们使用到的很多东西其实都在 MetaMask 的文档里有
If you go to their basic section,
如果你前往他们的基础部分
they talk a little bit about the provider,
他们会谈论一些关于 "Provider" 的内容
which is this window dot Aetherium,
正是这个 "window.ethereum"
you can read how to actually interact directly with meta mask in the meta mask documentation as well.
你也可以在 MetaMask 的文档中读到直接与 MetaMask 进行交互的方法
Now using window dot Aetherium is just one of the ways we're actually going to connect to the blockchain,
使用 "window.ethereum" 只是我们连接区块链的方式之一
there's actually multiple ways
实际上还有很多其它方式
because there's multiple different kinds of wallets out there.
因为还有很多其它种类的钱包存在
But for now, we're just going to pretend that window dot Aetherium and meta mask is the only extension out there.
但现在，我们只假设 "window.ethereum" 和 MetaMask 就是唯一的扩展
So what we want to do is we want to check to see if this wind of that Aetherium exists.
所以我们要做的就是检查这个 "window.ethereum" 是否存在
This is the first thing that we should be doing.
这是我们应该做的第一件事
Because if this doesn't exist, this means that they can't connect to the blockchain,
因为，如果它不存在，那就意味着它们无法连接到区块链上
one of the first things that we're going to want to do
所以我们要做的第一件事就是
is we're going to want to check to see if that exists.
要检查它是否存在
So we can do something like if we can say type of window that Aetherium does not equal, undefined.
我们可以这样做 `if (typeof window.ethereum !== "undefined")
Then we'll do console dot log, I see a meta mask.
接着是 `console.log("I see a metamask!")`
So now if we save, we come back to our front end,
现在，如果我们保存，返回前端
we do see I see a Metamask.
我们确实看到了 "I see a metamask!"
I've got a Google Chrome up without Metamask that
我有一个没安装 MetaMask 的 Google Chrome 浏览器
if we look in the console, and we hit refresh
如果我们看一下控制台("Console")并点击刷新
it the same URL where our live server is running.
这和我们的 "Live Server" 运行的是同一个 URL
We don't see that I see a meta mask
我们没有看到 "I see a metamask!"
because it doesn't see a meta mask.
因为它确实没见到 MetaMask
We can do else. console dot log, no Metamask
我们可以这样 `else
refresh, we still see ICD a meta mask where we have a meta mask.
刷新，我们还是可以在有 MetaMask 的浏览器看到 "I see a metamask!"
You don't have to open up a browser without one
你倒是不必非得打开一个没有 MetaMask 的浏览器
but we see no meta mask for Chrome because it doesn't see a meta mask.
但我们可以在 Chrome 浏览器中看到 "No metamask!"，因为它并没有看到 MetaMask
Now what we could do is We can automatically try to connect to meta mask
现在我们可以尝试自动连接到 MetaMask
if we see that there is a meta mask, right?
如果我们看到这里有 MetaMask 的话，对吧？
Remember how before,
还记得之前怎么做的么
when we hit that connect button meta mask popped up and said, Are you sure you want to connect?
当我们点击 "Connect" 按钮时 MetaMask 会弹出来，并询问你是否要进行连接
So what we can do is, and you can, again,
所以我们该怎么做，再提醒一下
you can find this in the meta mask docs, we can run this eath request accounts method,
你可以在 MetaMask 的文档找到我们要运行的这个 "eth_requestAccounts" 方法
which is basically going to be how we connect our Metamask.
基本上它就是我们连接到 MetaMask 的方法
Now, this is specified by a new EIP
现在，这是由一个新 EIP 进行规定的
and an older documentations. And in older tutorials, you might see Aetherium dot enable,
在一些旧的文档和旧的教程中，你可能会看到 "ethereum.enable()"
which essentially does the exact same thing.
它们基本上就是同一个东西
So what we could do here is we could say, a cerium, or excuse me, window dot Aetherium dot request.
所以我们可以在这里说 `ethereum`，抱歉，应该是 `window.ethereum.request()`
And we could put method F request accounts. And we'll save that.
我们可以在里面放入 ``，我们保存一下
Now if we go back to our browser, we'll actually see,
现在，如果我们返回浏览器，我们就能看到
you'll actually see Metamask, go ahead and pop up and say, let's connect
你就可以看到 MetaMask 真的弹了出来，并让我们进行连接
so we can choose an account. And we'll hit Connect,
我们可以选择一个账户，点击 "Connect"
will automatically connect our meta mask to our website.
它会自动把我们的 MetaMask 连接到我们的网站
And now if we look at our meta mask, we can see this little connected thing.
现在看一下我们的 MetaMask，我们可以看到这么一个小的“已连接”("Connected")
It's saying that our account one is now connected to our website.
它说的是，我们的 Account1 已经连接到了我们的网站上
This means that the website can now make API calls to our meta mask,
这意味着，这个网站可以对我们的 MetaMask 进行 API 调用了
we still have to be the ones to approve them.
我们仍然需要自己批准它们
But it can go ahead and connect and try to run transactions,
但它可以自行连接并尝试执行交易
which is awesome, which is what we want.
很好，这正是我们想要的
If you want to disconnect, we can go ahead and click that little button and hit disconnect this account.
如果你想要断开连接，可以点击这个小按钮并点击“断开此账户的链接”("Disconnect this account")
Well that we have our code currently is
现在我们代码的情况是
anytime we hit refresh, this is going to pop up which is going to be really annoying.
每次我们点击刷新，这个都会弹出来，真的是很烦人
So what we're going to do instead is
所以我们要做的是
we're going to wrap this up into an asynchronous function,
把这里封装成一个异步函数
the exact same as we've been doing,
就和我们之前做的一样
we'll do we'll create an async function called Connect.
我们来创建一个 `async function connect()`
And we'll wrap it up these curly braces here.
并把这些内容包裹在这对花括号内
And then we'll just format this a little bit to make it look nicer.
接着我们稍微调整一下格式化，让它看起来更好看一些
And now if we save, we go back to our website, and we refresh. And we go ahead and disconnect.
现在如果我们保存并刷新网站，然后断开连接
If we refresh Metamask won't keep asking us
现在我们再次刷新，MetaMask 就不会一直再询问我们
Hey, do you want to connect Hey, do you want to connect here do you want to connect,
是否要进行连接，是否要进行连接，是否要进行连接了
because we need to call this connect function
因为我们还需要调用这个 "connect" 函数
where we can do that is we can add a little button here.
我们可以在这里添加一个小按钮来实现这个功能
So right underneath our script tag, we're going to add a button tag.
所以在我们的 "" 标签下面，我们要添加一个 "" 标签
So this is the opening button tag. And then here's the closing button tag.
这个是 "" 标签的开头，而这个是 "" 标签的结尾
And inside the opening button tag declaration,
在这个开头的 "" 标签声明内部
we'll give it an ID, which will be Connect button.
我要给它一个 `id`，内容是 `connectButton`
And we'll say on click equals the Connect connects function.
接着我们会说 `onclick="connect()"` 也就是 `connect()` 函数
And we'll call this button connect
我们给这个按钮命名为 "Connect"
in between these little button tags, we'll call it connect
在这两个 "" 标签之间，我们把它称为 "Connect"
will say when we click it will call the Connect function.
当我们点击它的时候就是在调用 `connect()` 函数
So if we save, and we go back to our front end,
所以如果我们保存一下，然后回到我们的前端
we can now see we have a little Connect button.
现在我们可以看到一个小小的 "Connect" 按钮
And now if we press Connect, Metamask is going to pop up,
现在如果我们按下 "Connect"，MetaMask 就会弹出来
we'll hit next and connect like that. And boom, now we are connected.
我们点击“下一步”("Next")然后是“连接”("Connect")，嘭，现在我们已经连接上了
And we can even do a little await here so that we wait for this to finish before moving on.
我们甚至可以在这里加一个 `await` 这样我们就可以等待它完成以后再继续后续操作
And then after we connect, we can say console dot log connected.
然后，在我们连接上以后，我们可以说 `console.log("connected")
So let's actually go ahead and test this out, we'll go back to Metamask. we'll disconnect here,
让我们来实际测试一下，回到 MetaMask 断开连接
try to never be on Main net if we don't have to be.
如果没有必要，尽量不要使用主网络
And let's go ahead run connect, we'll hit Next connect.
让我们继续，运行 "Connect" 点击“下一步”("Next")，“连接”("Connect")
And now we see a little console dot log come out saying connected. Okay, great.
现在我们看倒，一个小的 "console.log" 出来说 "connected"，OK 很好
We can also update our website accordingly.
我们可以相应地更新我们的网站
So that we can let users know that we're connected.
这样我们就能让用户知道，我们已经连接上了
So we can grab the connect button element ID
所以我们可以获取这个 "Connect" 按钮的元素 "ID"
and say that we're connected once we're connected.
并且一旦连接成功，就说我们已经连接上了
So after we await to be connected, we can go ahead and do document dot get element by ID Connect button.
所以在我们等待连接完成之后，我们可以执行 `document.getElementById("connectButton")
And then we'll say dot inner HTML equals connected like that.
接着是 `.innerHTML = "Connected!"`
And then instead of saying no minimize down here, we'll do just the opposite.
然后，这里就不再说 "No metamask" 了，我们要在这做相反的事
So we'll copy this line.
所以我们复制这一行
And instead of connected, we'll say please install meta mask.
替换掉 "Connected!"，我们说 "Please install metamask!"
And we'll save we'll go back to our front end, we'll hit connect.
保存一下，然后回到前端，点击 "Connect"
And now if we're already connected, it'll just automatically go to connected.
现在，如果我们已经连接过了，这里就会自动连接
If we're not connected, it'll pop up, we'll get connected.
如果我们还没有连接，它就会弹出来，提示我们进行连接
And now we have this button that says connected, which is great.
现在我们的按钮就会说 "Connected!"，非常好
So now we already know that we're connected.
现在我们就知道我们已经连接成功了
So we've connected our Metamask to our front end.
所以，我们已经把 MetaMask 连接到我们的前端上了
Now we want to actually go ahead and do some functions here.
现在我们想要继续实现更多功能
And this is where we want to create some more functions and some more buttons
这里就是我们要创建更多函数和按钮的地方
that are going to use ethers that package that we become so familiar with.
这些函数和按钮将使用我们非常熟悉的 ethers 包
Now, as we code,
现在，随着我们编写代码
our script section is going to get bigger and bigger and bigger.
我们的 "" 部分将会变得越来越大
So oftentimes, we actually want to put our code in a JavaScript file itself.
因此实际上，我们往往会将代码放在一个独立的 JavaScript 文件中
So we're gonna go ahead, come over here, we're going to create a new file,
所以我们继续，来这里，创建一个新文件
and we'll call it index dot j s.
我们称它为 "index.js"
And instead of putting our JavaScript in these script tags,
我们不会再把 JavaScript 代码都放到这里的 "" 标签里了
we're going to put it in this index and then import this index file into our HTML.
而是会放到这个 "index" 文件里，并将它导入到我们的 HTML 中
And the way that we're going to do that
实现这个操作的方法是
is we're actually just going to grab this function.
我们先获取这里的函数
We're going to copy it, delete everything for now.
把它复制下来，暂时先删掉这些内容
We're going to paste it into our end ext dot j s,
然后粘贴到我们的 "index.js" 里来
and then in our index dot HTML, we're just going to tell our script tag to use index.js.
接着在我们的 "index.html" 里，直接让我们的 "" 标签使用 "index.js"
So we're just going to say the source is going to be equal to dot slash index dot j s.
所以这里要这么写 `src="./index.js"`
And then we're going to say, the type of this is going to be text slash JavaScript.
接下来的内容是 `type="text/javascript"`
Now if we save that, and we save our index dot HTML,
现在，我们保存一下我们的 "index.html"
we come back to our front end, we do a little refresh.
回到我们的前端，稍微刷新一下
And we make sure that we go ahead and disconnect.
并且确保我们是断开连接的状态
And we do another refresh, we can see
再刷新一次，我们可以看到
that even with our index.js in a different file,
即使我们的 "index.js" 是在一个不同的文件中
because we're doing src equals index.js, and we're importing it into our HTML,
因为我们执行了 `src = index.js`，把它导入了我们的 HTML 中
when we hit Connect, it still calls our Connect function.
所以当我们点击 "Connect" 的时候，它仍然会调用我们的 `connect()` 函数
That's how we can kind of separate our JavaScript into its own js file
这样我们就可以将我们的 JavaScript 代码分离到一个独立的 JS 文件中
that we're a little bit more familiar with.
这样的方式会让我们感到更加熟悉
Now, if you look in the GitHub repo associated with this course,
现在，如果你查看一下课程关联的 GitHub 仓库
and you look in the index dot j s,
并查看一下 "index.js"
you'll see our Connect function, we've added some quality of life stuff,
你会看到我们的 "connect()" 函数添加了一些优化的内容
we've added some try catches just to make handling errors a little bit better,
我们添加了一些 `try-catch` 语句，为了能够更好地处理错误情况
you can go ahead and add those try catches in yourself if you'd like.
如果你想的话，可以自行添加这些 `try-catch` 语句
But I'm not going to demo them in this video here.
但我就不在视频里做演示了